<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Jeremy Smith</title>
<subtitle type="text">Composer</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2017-03-10T19:49:24-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal 5]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-5" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-5</id>
  <published>2016-08-09T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-08-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The days are starting to fly by quickly. With 15 days remaining I am truly beginning to dread the last. I can honestly say I am getting used to this sort of lifestyle. Camille left for Marshall (which is about 30 or so minutes away) very early this morning for a long awaited dentist appointment, and Ginna was gone to town by 9 o’clock. With the entire house empty I felt as though I had the entirety of the Smoky Mountains to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wrote the most beautiful music that I have ever written. I’m not quite sure where it came from, but at times it almost felt like I was taking dictation rather than composing. I got so wrapped up in it that in fact I think we might alter the story of this little ballet just tad. It would be a shame to let this music go to waste over something as trivial as a carefully and expertly crafted story arch which took months to develop. Spoken like a true composer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran into town to send out some (very) rough drafts of the first act to my friend who wrote (and is currently rewriting) the story. I grabbed another burger at the restaurant and used the wifi to quickly check in with my friends at the drum corps. They seem to be making quite a bit of progress! I do wish I could be there, but I am here right now. I will be there soon enough (and hopefully with around 25-30 more minutes of music).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I have to do a little work around the house as part of my work trade with the residency. Nothing so bad. A little computer cataloging and possibly some weeding in the garden. After that I will continue to revise Act One. I think that i am getting very close. I am excited about starting Act Two, but I can’t get ahead of myself. It will be nice to take a small break from composing and reading in the morning to occupy myself in a different way. Nietzsche famously said “All truly great thoughts are conceived by walking”… let’s hope that the same is true of pulling weeds.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-5&quot;&gt;Journal 5&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on August 09, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal 4]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-4" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-4</id>
  <published>2016-06-08T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today began about 30 minutes later than the past few days have. After grabbing a quick breakfast and a few cups of coffee I got right to work. Seven hours of work harvested around a minute and a half of music, but I must say that it is probably some of the strongest material I have ever written. I stepped outside and watched Camille work on her mosaic today for a little while. She asked how I was getting along. “Strange music today, Camille”, I said. “Stranger zen yesterday?” she asked. I told her it was much stranger than yesterday. Her mosaic is really starting to come together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ginna came back around 2 o’clock today (her name is apparently spelt that way). She gave me a book of her short stories. Pretty discomforting stuff (Especially the font. I have always been sensitive to things like that. Seemingly small details can ruin the aesthetic of something). Her writing is actually really good. Very descriptive. I feel like I can relate to a lot of the things she is writing, but I’m sure she would like to continue thinking that no one can. Some people really enjoy being on their own island. I’m trying to get off of mine. I ended up reading the majority of her book today during breaks. It will be interesting to talk to her more tonight. I have read most of her book and I am sure she has heard plenty of my music between my banging on the piano and the computer playback through my speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were quite a few disruptions today. Around 3 of the board members from the residency stopped by individually to make sure that my work was going well and to ask if I was enjoying my stay. They were all incredibly nice and I managed to keep a pleasant facade while trying to avoid telling them that my work would be going much better if I could get a few minutes void of a knock on my door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a basement here. It is actually really big, and they’ve used it to host events with over 100 people. Today Camille told me that she had dug the entire thing by hand in over the course of two years in the early 80’s. I asked her how she managed to do such a thing, and she said “Little by little. Day by day. Big tasks become smaller, but you must stay at it!”. That is absolutely incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 4 down. Still much work to be done, but I feel like I have done a decent amount of digging.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-4&quot;&gt;Journal 4&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 08, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal 3]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-3" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-3</id>
  <published>2016-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I woke up this morning well rested and ready to work. Scene 2 is 98% complete. I figure the endings of each scene will change as the next scene takes shape so I’m not going to sweat the last 10 seconds or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However ready I was to work didn’t quite help and I struggled to come up with anything worth putting down for close to an hour. Camille dropped by to ask how my work was coming along. I told her “You know how it is. Sometimes it is difficult to find the jumping off point”. She just smiled and said “Yes. The beginning is always very hard, but ven you find it then it vill go very quickly”. Not long after I found that long sought after jumping off point, and Camille was right in saying that it would go very quickly. I thought of an interesting little motif that I liked quite a bit, and in a way which is not unlike a lot of my previous work I found a way of using it to create a number of different ideas as well as some interesting textures which served as great transition material from section to section. This scene has a pretty lengthy piano solo. It’s a funny little tune. It is really not like anything I have ever written. This scene went very quickly and I reached the 2 and a half minute point around 5:00 o’clock. After some quick revisions I felt satisfied with the day’s work by around 6:00.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after I finished for the day about 5 people showed up and brought a new piano into my room. Some real rough and tough mountain men. They continued to hassle me about playing the piano for them. I told them I was no pianist, but they were incredibly persistent. I thought “Well, the men just carried a piano a hundred yards. The least I can do is play something for them”. I played the only thing I knew that I would play without error which was the first movement of “Metamorphosis” by Philip Glass. I have always really liked that piece. After about 5 minutes of the same 3 phrases over and over again I could tell they had had enough piano and enough Philip Glass to last them for the rest of their lives. They stayed and talked with me for a little while longer. They were very nice, humble, and unassuming people, but they could use a shower. They left a thick scent of body odor behind in my room which was as heavy as I assume that piano was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After talking to them and having been satisfied with my work I decided to take a short trip into town to pick up some fresh milk and eggs. I stopped and had a burger at the local restaurant. It is a small one road town. The sort of town where it seems you either move away, work at the restaurant, or work at the other restaurant, but everyone there seems very content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back to my car I was stopped by a girl who appeared to be around my age. She looked as though she was about to give out under the weight of a large backpack. She asked “Do you know where the hostile is?”. Thinking to myself that in a town with all of 6 buildings that if one of them was a hostile it shouldn’t be difficult to find I replied “No. I’m sorry. I am not from here”. Never in the history of time has such an innocent statement started such a conversation. She told me that her name was “Unbreakable Kelly”, although she looked a little broken today. She confessed to having survived a bear attack this morning and to having hitchhiked to Hot Springs after hiking around 15 miles. She informed me that she had nowhere to stay and that she was low on cash. I advised that she sleep in the forest since that is where she had presumably been sleeping for the past few weeks. I think she just wanted money. I didn’t give her any, but I did assure her that she was “Unbreakable”. Yesterday all I wanted was conversation. Today all i wanted was to get out of that one. What fickle creatures we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I will stick around the house. That Jenna woman is supposedly coming back at some point. Let’s hope a few nights in an air conditioned hotel has done her some well.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-3&quot;&gt;Journal 3&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 07, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal 2]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-2" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-2</id>
  <published>2016-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I worked for ten hours today. I got about 2 and half minutes of music done. That finishes act one scene one. Tomorrow is scene two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That Jenna woman left around 10:30 or so this morning. She said she was going to stay in a hotel for the next two nights. She seemed kind of distressed. Complaining about the heat in the house, and that she had no fan. She also talked to herself as she was packing her car. Made a real big thing of it. I don’t know. It feels fine in here to me, but Im also not a woman in my 40’s so… who knows?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My work went well, but I am very exhausted. After I finished I went outside and talked to Camille. I had barely spoken a work all day, and she was very good conversation. She is working on a mosaic of two fish for a downstairs bathroom (the shower of which will be inside of a large bay window overlooking the front yard. Seems like a strange place for a shower, but Im not in charge of all that). We talked about how she cuts the stone and lays in particular places to create not just the picture, but the texture. It is interesting how similar all of it is to music, but i guess most everything is connected and analogous if you try hard enough to make it so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was nice to talk to someone though. I didn’t realize how quickly I would grow lonely. We really are just slammed over the head with conversation and external stimulation constantly. It is strange to not be. I know that its not a feeling of boredom. I don’t long to look at my phone or anything like that. It really is just a feeling of loneliness. Going a day without talking to anyone is hard. Its an experience like one that I have never had. I am enjoying it for the most part. They said that someone else is coming to stay and work in around 6 days. That’ll be nice. Here is to hoping its not another heat flash prone complainer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day two down. I have 3 more days until I finish the first act. I think after that I might take a day to wander into town. Apparently there is a pretty good pizza place. Not looking forward to driving back up that mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-2&quot;&gt;Journal 2&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 06, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal 1]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-1" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-1</id>
  <published>2016-06-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got on the road this morning at around 8 o’clock. I had planned on leaving at 7, but upon waking I realized how ambitious of a goal that had been. Not long after starting the trip I began to notice a slight incline on the road. Little did I know it was just the beginning. The drive was a little more than 4 hours, and the incline became progressively steeper the entire way. I got off of the interstate and began to drive through thick fog and forest. I looked down at my phone which read “no service”, and that was it. I became panicked for a moment because I had been following direction from my phones’ GPS system and I was afraid that the directions would stop in the absence of service. Here I am. My tiny car loaded down with books, clothes, vinyls, water, and food driving through some god forsaken forest with rain pouring down relentlessly on my windshield, and I am completely lost. I remember thinking “Good god… If I get lost out here they’ll never find me.” Luckily my phone continued to point me in the right direction. I have no idea how that works, but I’m glad that there is someone somewhere that does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I drove through the fog on the windiest and steepest roads that I have ever laid eyes on. Eventually I wound up on a dirt road which seemed to go on forever, and as my car bounced and jerked on the gravel beneath me I saw the house in the distance. A giant house made almost completely out of windows. I pulled up to the house and was met almost immediately by a very small old woman who wore a funny little yellow rain hat, and was missing a significant portion of her right arm. Through a thick french accent she told me that her name was Camille. I guess she is the groundskeeper or sorts. She welcomed me and began to show me into the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a very oddly designed home. Three stories with a strange stained glass staircase connecting the top floor to the bottom. The top floor is mostly bedrooms and this is where I met the other current resident. She told me that her name was Jenna. She seems to be in her early 40’s and has a very short haircut with a blue streak in the front. We spoke briefly and she seemed very cordial and nice enough (despite the fact that her appearance gives me the impression of someone you would find yelling at their kids in a Wal-mart). Camille took me onto the ground floor and through a large open room which they call the library. There are books shoved into every nook and cranny that they could have possibly put books in. Many of the books are in French. We walked through the library and into a very small hallway which led to a door. Camille opened the door and said (in that same accent) “Dis is vere you vill stay and compose”. I walked through the door and into a huge U shaped room which contained only a table, a piano, and a very small bed. With that the tour completed and Camille said she would leave me to my work. I unpacked and started to compose. After a few hours (I have no idea what time it is) I realized that I was very hungry. I made soup and sat down to write this journal. Will probably work a little more later. That is all for today. It is very quiet here. I am not sure just what to think yet.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/journal-1&quot;&gt;Journal 1&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 05, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>