<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Jeremy Smith</title>
<subtitle type="text">Composer</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2017-03-24T18:44:38-05:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 19]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-19" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-19</id>
  <published>2016-06-23T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today’s journal comes a little early. I wrote the story about Camille. I gave her the piece that I wrote for her. I took pictures. Swept, mopped, and dusted. I finished my work trade. I packed. I took a deep breath and I looked around. My last day in this house. It has been an incredible experience. I have accomplished everything I set out to and more. A few weeks ago I entered this house a little nervous. Tomorrow, I will leave. It has become a home. I have made friends, had conversations, hiked, swam, thought… oh yea… and wrote a 25 minute ballet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight I will get to bed early. Tomorrow I will pack the car and leave to meet my friends at Music City Drum Corps in Nashville. This will start the second leg of my summer. I will be in Nashville for about 4 days before we embark on tour. On July 9th I will take a bus back from Madison, Wisconsin to Chicago. Then Chicago to Nashville. I will do 3 weeks of teaching (and 4 days back in Florence) before heading back for the last bit of tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All things must come to an end, and this residency is no different. It has been a trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing behind me, everything in front of me, as is ever so on the road”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-19&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 19&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 23, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 18]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-18" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-18</id>
  <published>2016-06-22T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was nice. I woke up and began work revising the first act. I added around a minute and a half to it (along with cleaning up a few notation and score issues). I am sitting at around 22 and a half minutes of music. Not a bad haul for a little over 2 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I finished working I did a little bit for my work trade. Part of what they wanted me to do, in addition the cleaning and outside work, was to interview Camille and write a little story about my time here for the website. This woman is absolutely remarkable. A self taught architect who wanted to design a place for artists to create. She kept saying this word (through her thick French accent) that had influenced her. I couldn’t quite make it out at first… she was saying Cathedral. She explained that like the cathedrals in the Middle Ages she wants to build as much as she can before she passes on. When she dies someone else will take the responsibility of the ongoing construction. In reality she has plans made for structures on this property that might take four lifetimes. Wouldn’t it be crazy to be capable of thinking that far outside of yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are all sorts of strange little features in this house that really make no sense. Doors in strange places and windows in the ceiling. The kind of things you look at and say “Why did she do that?”. Her and her husband were married on an airplane 2,000 feet in the sky. They drove around the country in a van for almost a year looking for a place to settle down. When they arrived here they turned the van off. They lived here for 44 years. He died in this house around a decade ago after a long battle with muscular sclerosis. Suddenly everything made sense. The strange doors were for his wheelchair. The odd windows were so he could look up and see the stars from his bed. On his last night she said he kept saying “Drive me there. Drive me there”. She said she has no idea what he meant. She kind of laughed and shrugged while saying “I drove him crazy his whole life. Maybe this is what he meant.” He is buried just a little ways from this house under a stone that is inscribed with the phrase “Drive me there”. She must have really loved him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I bumped into her as she busily scuttled around the house. I said “I’m sorry, Camille!”. She just looked at me and after a long pause said “I am going to miss you!”. “You are?” I said. She said “Of course. I think what it is that you are doing is very interesting. Plus, you are all around nice guy” (Her English is still very broken). I just looked at her and smiled. I said “I’m going to miss you too, Camille”. I am going to miss her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone seems to leave her something when they leave. All over the house there are sculptures, paintings, portraits, poems, and short stories. Some of the work is of her, and some of it is for her.  I wanted to leave her with something as well. I wrote a very short and very simple little piano piece in the form of a chaconne. I am going to print it out and give it to her on my last day (which will now be Friday). It is entitled “Drive Me There” with the subtitle “For Camille”.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-18&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 18&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 22, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 17]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-17" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-17</id>
  <published>2016-06-21T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was a good day. I finished Act Three. I now have a first draft of the entire production. Currently it sits at around 21 minutes. Tomorrow I will begin the revision process on Act One. I hope that after a few weeks away from the first act I can expand a little more on the ideas which I thought were lacking. The goal was to leave with close to 30 minutes of music. I feel very confident that this goal will be met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I finished working for the day I started on my work trade. I have to finish 5 and a half hours of work around and for the house over the next 3 days. I have always said that one of my biggest strengths is being able to put things off until the very last second. Maybe one day I will try to get better about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 days left&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-17&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 17&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 21, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 16]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-16" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-16</id>
  <published>2016-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Shane left around 9:30 this morning. Camille left for Asheville around 10:30 so I had the entire house to myself today. I got a little bit of work done, and finished some more of my work trade. One of the responsibilities I have been given for the work trade is fixing a guitar. I thought I had entered this program just a tad over my head by trying to write the music for a ballet. Then I started trying to fix a guitar. I think I can do it, but I cannot promise that there won’t be wood glue all over it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 days and 5 nights left.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-16&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 16&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 20, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 15]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-15" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-15</id>
  <published>2016-06-19T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I worked for about 6 hours today, and finished 3 minutes of music. I am at the halfway point for the final act. I hope I can finish in the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing work Shane and I went down into town for some nachos we have been eyeing for the past week or so. It his last night at Azule. He will leave tomorrow. After that it will be back down to Camille and I for just a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-15&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 15&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 19, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 14]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-14" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-14</id>
  <published>2016-06-18T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Betsey left this morning around 10 o’clock. After that Shane and I both started to work. I finished around 2 minutes of Act III which was ultimately my goal for the today. Pretty quiet day in the mountains. Nothing left to do but make dinner and wait for the sun to set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 14 down.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-14&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 14&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 18, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 13]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-13" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-13</id>
  <published>2016-06-17T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;134 years ago today a man was born who would forever change the history of Western music. This man would go on to pioneer 3 distinct movements and become one of the most influential figures of 20th century music. His name was Igor Stravinsky. Today at Azule I took a day off of composing and we all took the day to celebrate Stravinsky’s birthday… and Betsey’s last day at the residency (Honestly I was the only one celebrating Stravinsky’s birthday). It was a very fun and relaxing day. A lot of sitting around outside, talking, enjoying one another’s company, food, and la vie boheme-ing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I will jump into Act III.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-13&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 13&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 17, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 12]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-12" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-12</id>
  <published>2016-06-16T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Act Two is complete. I am super happy with it. It lasts a little over 6 minutes. That gives me 8 more days to finish the third act and to revise the entire production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended up getting a definitive answer to the abandoned house. Apparently it isn’t abandoned, and some wise mountain guru lives there and provides council over bonfires to the youth of the town. Strange. At least we know that it was our overactive imaginations and that we aren’t surrounded by cult members or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two other residents and I have really hit it off. It is exactly what I had hoped for. We share meals, inspirations, and discuss our creation process. I feel like I have learned a lot just being around them. This second week has been a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-12&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 12&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 16, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 11]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-11" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-11</id>
  <published>2016-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was a pretty great day of work. I am actually far ahead of where I thought I would be in Act Two. I feel very confident that I will be able to finish it tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After everyone here was finished for the day we all decided to go get some pizza at the local restaurant. On our ascension back up the mountain we noticed for the first time a very small church which seems to be carefully placed at the top of a extremely long and winding road. We all decided that a church this far out in the Smoky Mountains must be one of those churches where they handle snakes. That topic quickly passed into a conversation about our mutual fear of snakes. The idea of fear lead us to the unspoken thing which had been on all of our minds since our individual arrivals which was the fact that we are in the middle of nowhere in a house that has no locks on the door. We began discussing at length the similarities of our current lodging and just about every plot of any horror movie which has ever been made. After we had gotten through that conversation we all went for a walk around the vast wilderness surrounding the house. We stumbled onto a house which was said to have been abandoned long ago. As we passed the abandoned house I noticed in the window what appeared to be the light of a candle. As we continued walking and the angle of our view into the window changed we all noticed about 15 candles and a bonfire in the backyard. We started walking noticeably faster while conversing about what must be going on in the abandoned house which… was obviously some sort of satanic ritual. After getting back to the house and indulging our wildest imaginings concerning the oddity of these candles we came to the agreement that none of us would be able to sleep until we had an answer to this abandoned house once and for all. We marched back down to the house to find that all of the candles had been extinguished, and that the house looked as abandoned as ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say that imagination is a very important part of being an artist, but maybe when you get three imaginations together in the middle of nowhere things can get a little out of hand. All in all with the talk of snakes, psychopathic ax wielders, witches, and rituals it has been a pretty fun night! One that is unlike any I have ever had. It is also the first time I have seen a man who is close to his thirties check under his bed for monsters.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-11&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 11&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 15, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 10]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-10" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-10</id>
  <published>2016-06-14T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today has been a pretty slow day. I got around a minute and a half of music done. I took a few naps and kind of lounged around for most of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three of us all sat up talking last night until very late. It is nice to have some more people here after having been alone for a week. It has changed the dynamic in the house. Everyone stays very quiet and works all day on their respective projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been super hot in the house today. I think that it ended up getting close to 95 degrees outside, and probably at least 85 in the house. I can hear thunder rolling in the distance. I hope that it rains like crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-10&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 10&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 14, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 9]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-9" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-9</id>
  <published>2016-06-13T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got a little bit of work done early this morning. Around 1 o’clock we went out hiking. Some of the views out here are incredible. The mountains seem to go on forever. I have really never seen anything like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we got back another resident had arrived. A writer in his very late 20’s. He is working on his second novel while he is here. He gave me a copy of his first novel which I have read a little bit of. It is a very interesting idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I will sojourn on into Act Two.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-9&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 9&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 13, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 8]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-8" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-8</id>
  <published>2016-06-12T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today has been an incredibly successful and productive day. Act One is complete. At least for now. It runs around 10 minutes long. I will begin on Act Two tomorrow. It is a little shorter, and I am hoping to have it done in around 3 days. That will give me a little over a week to finish the third and final act and revise the entire product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing I ran into town to send out some band arrangements and sound files (and to grab another burger. They are starting to recognize me at the restaurant). I had driven all the way down into Hot Springs… and then I noticed I had forgotten my wallet. I have driven up and down the mountain twice today, and although I still go well under the speed limit I am really starting to get used to that drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new person arrived while I was in town. After I got back we spent around an hour or so exploring the house and talking. It is nice to have someone my age around. Tomorrow we are going to section hike some of the Appalachian Trail, and later this week we are going to make the trek to Asheville. I had hoped I was going to be able to make it to Asheville while I was here. I have never been, but everyone has always told me I would love it there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today marks a full week since my arrival at Azule. I have loved every second. Only 12 days left. I am not looking forward to that last trip down the mountain, but I don’t have to think about that just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-8&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 8&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 12, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 7]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-7" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-7</id>
  <published>2016-06-11T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not much to write about today. After staying up until around 3:30 this morning I was up by 9:30 and at it again. I worked for 13 hours today only taking the occasional short break and eating meals while working. I spent most of the day locked away in my room. I am feeling very determined and very tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow a new person is supposed to arrive. Apparently a sculptor. Should be interested to see this person work. I hope this next person is a little more fun than the last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I will finish Act one.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-7&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 7&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 11, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 6]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-6" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-6</id>
  <published>2016-06-10T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was a little of an off day. By “off” I mean a break from composing. I did a little work on the computer for the residency program. After that I weeded the flower beds for about an hour. I had thought it had been pretty cold in North Carolina. That was until I spent an hour in the noon sun pulling weeds. Every time I do work like that I am instantly transported to the days of my teenage years. I remember being woken up early to go put up fences with my dad. He used to say that I needed to learn the value of a dollar. I have come to know that what he meant was that it was important for me to find that nothing comes easy, and that anything worth doing was worth doing right. He wanted to teach me that hard work is something to enjoy… to be proud of. What I came to know (at least at the time) was that I hated being outside, I hated the bugs, and that I wasn’t blessed with the physique necessary to carry around heavy stacks of wood or rolls of chain link with the ease that it seemed he and my brother enjoyed. I like to think that I have applied those hard earned lessons that my father tried so earnestly to bestow on me into the road that I am forging for myself. Nonetheless, I found working outside today to be a rather wearisome chore. I can confess to counting down the minutes that I had to be outside pulling weeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I composed very little, but I thought quite a bit. I am looking forward to getting a running start at tomorrow’s work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I sat outside talking to Camille. The subject inevitably turned towards politics. It is interesting to talk to someone who has seen so much. I tend to side with Socrates in thinking that everyone truly wants what they think is best. Most people do what they think is the most beneficial thing within their certain situation, and the older I get the more I realize that no one is ever completely sure of which road to take. We all just seem so divided. I think the thing that we can’t lose sight of is the vision. The bigger picture. Where are we going? Where do we want to go? This “little” issue seems to be where we all are the most divided, but I think that the division comes much more so from a lack of vision than from a difference of opinion. I don’t have any answers, but that doesn’t make the conversation any less enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight I have been working (and will continue to work) on a marching band opener! I have enjoyed my little reprieve from composing today. It feels like my first day in the mountains rather than my sixth day in a room with a piano. I guess that you have to stop and smell the roses and so on. Tomorrow I will be right back at it, but tonight I will enjoy a little retrospection and of course Blues! in the key of band.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-6&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 6&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 10, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 5]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-5" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-5</id>
  <published>2016-06-09T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The days are starting to fly by quickly. With 15 days remaining I am truly beginning to dread the last. I can honestly say I am getting used to this sort of lifestyle. Camille left for Marshall (which is about 30 or so minutes away) very early this morning for a long awaited dentist appointment, and Ginna was gone to town by 9 o’clock. With the entire house empty I felt as though I had the entirety of the Smoky Mountains to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wrote the most beautiful music that I have ever written. I’m not quite sure where it came from, but at times it almost felt like I was taking dictation rather than composing. I got so wrapped up in it that in fact I think we might alter the story of this little ballet just tad. It would be a shame to let this music go to waste over something as trivial as a carefully and expertly crafted story arch which took months to develop. Spoken like a true composer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran into town to send out some (very) rough drafts of the first act to my friend who wrote (and is currently rewriting) the story. I grabbed another burger at the restaurant and used the wifi to quickly check in with my friends at the drum corps. They seem to be making quite a bit of progress! I do wish I could be there, but I am here right now. I will be there soon enough (and hopefully with around 25-30 more minutes of music).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I have to do a little work around the house as part of my work trade with the residency. Nothing so bad. A little computer cataloging and possibly some weeding in the garden. After that I will continue to revise Act One. I think that i am getting very close. I am excited about starting Act Two, but I can’t get ahead of myself. It will be nice to take a small break from composing and reading in the morning to occupy myself in a different way. Nietzsche famously said “All truly great thoughts are conceived by walking”… let’s hope that the same is true of pulling weeds.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-5&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 5&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 09, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 4]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-4" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-4</id>
  <published>2016-06-08T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today began about 30 minutes later than the past few days have. After grabbing a quick breakfast and a few cups of coffee I got right to work. Seven hours of work harvested around a minute and a half of music, but I must say that it is probably some of the strongest material I have ever written. I stepped outside and watched Camille work on her mosaic today for a little while. She asked how I was getting along. “Strange music today, Camille”, I said. “Stranger zen yesterday?” she asked. I told her it was much stranger than yesterday. Her mosaic is really starting to come together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ginna came back around 2 o’clock today (her name is apparently spelt that way). She gave me a book of her short stories. Pretty discomforting stuff (Especially the font. I have always been sensitive to things like that. Seemingly small details can ruin the aesthetic of something). Her writing is actually really good. Very descriptive. I feel like I can relate to a lot of the things she is writing, but I’m sure she would like to continue thinking that no one can. Some people really enjoy being on their own island. I’m trying to get off of mine. I ended up reading the majority of her book today during breaks. It will be interesting to talk to her more tonight. I have read most of her book and I am sure she has heard plenty of my music between my banging on the piano and the computer playback through my speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were quite a few disruptions today. Around 3 of the board members from the residency stopped by individually to make sure that my work was going well and to ask if I was enjoying my stay. They were all incredibly nice and I managed to keep a pleasant facade while trying to avoid telling them that my work would be going much better if I could get a few minutes void of a knock on my door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a basement here. It is actually really big, and they’ve used it to host events with over 100 people. Today Camille told me that she had dug the entire thing by hand in over the course of two years in the early 80’s. I asked her how she managed to do such a thing, and she said “Little by little. Day by day. Big tasks become smaller, but you must stay at it!”. That is absolutely incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 4 down. Still much work to be done, but I feel like I have done a decent amount of digging.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-4&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 4&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 08, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 3]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-3" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-3</id>
  <published>2016-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I woke up this morning well rested and ready to work. Scene 2 is 98% complete. I figure the endings of each scene will change as the next scene takes shape so I’m not going to sweat the last 10 seconds or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However ready I was to work didn’t quite help and I struggled to come up with anything worth putting down for close to an hour. Camille dropped by to ask how my work was coming along. I told her “You know how it is. Sometimes it is difficult to find the jumping off point”. She just smiled and said “Yes. The beginning is always very hard, but ven you find it then it vill go very quickly”. Not long after I found that long sought after jumping off point, and Camille was right in saying that it would go very quickly. I thought of an interesting little motif that I liked quite a bit, and in a way which is not unlike a lot of my previous work I found a way of using it to create a number of different ideas as well as some interesting textures which served as great transition material from section to section. This scene has a pretty lengthy piano solo. It’s a funny little tune. It is really not like anything I have ever written. This scene went very quickly and I reached the 2 and a half minute point around 5:00 o’clock. After some quick revisions I felt satisfied with the day’s work by around 6:00.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after I finished for the day about 5 people showed up and brought a new piano into my room. Some real rough and tough mountain men. They continued to hassle me about playing the piano for them. I told them I was no pianist, but they were incredibly persistent. I thought “Well, the men just carried a piano a hundred yards. The least I can do is play something for them”. I played the only thing I knew that I would play without error which was the first movement of “Metamorphosis” by Philip Glass. I have always really liked that piece. After about 5 minutes of the same 3 phrases over and over again I could tell they had had enough piano and enough Philip Glass to last them for the rest of their lives. They stayed and talked with me for a little while longer. They were very nice, humble, and unassuming people, but they could use a shower. They left a thick scent of body odor behind in my room which was as heavy as I assume that piano was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After talking to them and having been satisfied with my work I decided to take a short trip into town to pick up some fresh milk and eggs. I stopped and had a burger at the local restaurant. It is a small one road town. The sort of town where it seems you either move away, work at the restaurant, or work at the other restaurant, but everyone there seems very content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back to my car I was stopped by a girl who appeared to be around my age. She looked as though she was about to give out under the weight of a large backpack. She asked “Do you know where the hostile is?”. Thinking to myself that in a town with all of 6 buildings that if one of them was a hostile it shouldn’t be difficult to find I replied “No. I’m sorry. I am not from here”. Never in the history of time has such an innocent statement started such a conversation. She told me that her name was “Unbreakable Kelly”, although she looked a little broken today. She confessed to having survived a bear attack this morning and to having hitchhiked to Hot Springs after hiking around 15 miles. She informed me that she had nowhere to stay and that she was low on cash. I advised that she sleep in the forest since that is where she had presumably been sleeping for the past few weeks. I think she just wanted money. I didn’t give her any, but I did assure her that she was “Unbreakable”. Yesterday all I wanted was conversation. Today all i wanted was to get out of that one. What fickle creatures we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I will stick around the house. That Jenna woman is supposedly coming back at some point. Let’s hope a few nights in an air conditioned hotel has done her some well.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-3&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 3&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 07, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 2]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-2" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-2</id>
  <published>2016-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I worked for ten hours today. I got about 2 and half minutes of music done. That finishes act one scene one. Tomorrow is scene two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That Jenna woman left around 10:30 or so this morning. She said she was going to stay in a hotel for the next two nights. She seemed kind of distressed. Complaining about the heat in the house, and that she had no fan. She also talked to herself as she was packing her car. Made a real big thing of it. I don’t know. It feels fine in here to me, but Im also not a woman in my 40’s so… who knows?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My work went well, but I am very exhausted. After I finished I went outside and talked to Camille. I had barely spoken a work all day, and she was very good conversation. She is working on a mosaic of two fish for a downstairs bathroom (the shower of which will be inside of a large bay window overlooking the front yard. Seems like a strange place for a shower, but Im not in charge of all that). We talked about how she cuts the stone and lays in particular places to create not just the picture, but the texture. It is interesting how similar all of it is to music, but i guess most everything is connected and analogous if you try hard enough to make it so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was nice to talk to someone though. I didn’t realize how quickly I would grow lonely. We really are just slammed over the head with conversation and external stimulation constantly. It is strange to not be. I know that its not a feeling of boredom. I don’t long to look at my phone or anything like that. It really is just a feeling of loneliness. Going a day without talking to anyone is hard. Its an experience like one that I have never had. I am enjoying it for the most part. They said that someone else is coming to stay and work in around 6 days. That’ll be nice. Here is to hoping its not another heat flash prone complainer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day two down. I have 3 more days until I finish the first act. I think after that I might take a day to wander into town. Apparently there is a pretty good pizza place. Not looking forward to driving back up that mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-2&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 2&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 06, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal &#35 1]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-1" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-1</id>
  <published>2016-06-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-06-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Smith</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>jeremysmith222@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got on the road this morning at around 8 o’clock. I had planned on leaving at 7, but upon waking I realized how ambitious of a goal that had been. Not long after starting the trip I began to notice a slight incline on the road. Little did I know it was just the beginning. The drive was a little more than 4 hours, and the incline became progressively steeper the entire way. I got off of the interstate and began to drive through thick fog and forest. I looked down at my phone which read “no service”, and that was it. I became panicked for a moment because I had been following direction from my phones’ GPS system and I was afraid that the directions would stop in the absence of service. Here I am. My tiny car loaded down with books, clothes, vinyls, water, and food driving through some god forsaken forest with rain pouring down relentlessly on my windshield, and I am completely lost. I remember thinking “Good god… If I get lost out here they’ll never find me.” Luckily my phone continued to point me in the right direction. I have no idea how that works, but I’m glad that there is someone somewhere that does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I drove through the fog on the windiest and steepest roads that I have ever laid eyes on. Eventually I wound up on a dirt road which seemed to go on forever, and as my car bounced and jerked on the gravel beneath me I saw the house in the distance. A giant house made almost completely out of windows. I pulled up to the house and was met almost immediately by a very small old woman who wore a funny little yellow rain hat, and was missing a significant portion of her right arm. Through a thick french accent she told me that her name was Camille. I guess she is the groundskeeper or sorts. She welcomed me and began to show me into the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a very oddly designed home. Three stories with a strange stained glass staircase connecting the top floor to the bottom. The top floor is mostly bedrooms and this is where I met the other current resident. She told me that her name was Jenna. She seems to be in her early 40’s and has a very short haircut with a blue streak in the front. We spoke briefly and she seemed very cordial and nice enough (despite the fact that her appearance gives me the impression of someone you would find yelling at their kids in a Wal-mart). Camille took me onto the ground floor and through a large open room which they call the library. There are books shoved into every nook and cranny that they could have possibly put books in. Many of the books are in French. We walked through the library and into a very small hallway which led to a door. Camille opened the door and said (in that same accent) “Dis is vere you vill stay and compose”. I walked through the door and into a huge U shaped room which contained only a table, a piano, and a very small bed. With that the tour completed and Camille said she would leave me to my work. I unpacked and started to compose. After a few hours (I have no idea what time it is) I realized that I was very hungry. I made soup and sat down to write this journal. Will probably work a little more later. That is all for today. It is very quiet here. I am not sure just what to think yet.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-azule-journals/journal-1&quot;&gt;Journal &#35 1&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jeremy Smith at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Jeremy Smith&lt;/a&gt; on June 05, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>